So let's first just go through a couple of really useful words that we can use when we're talking about
因此，让我们首先通过几个非常有用的词，我们可以在谈论时使用它们
movies and TV and also how we can actually put some of them together to explain what we want to explain.
电影和电视，以及我们如何将其中一些放在一起来解释我们想要解释的内容。
OK.
好的。
So first very quickly let's just go through these the plot the plot of a movie is basically what happens
所以首先很快让我们来看看这些情节电影的情节基本上就是发生了什么
in the story line that the story follows the points along the way in the story.
在故事情节中，故事遵循故事中的点。
This is this is the plot doesn't have to be a movie doesn't have to be a TV series.
这就是情节不一定是电影不一定是电视剧。
But when you're if you need to when you're explaining what happens in a movie or a video game or whatever
但是当你需要解释电影、电子游戏或其他什么发生的事情时
to your friends you're actually explaining the plot to them.
对你的朋友，你实际上是在向他们解释情节。
OK.
好的。
The characters are the people who are in the video game or the movie or the TV series not real people.
角色是电子游戏、电影或电视剧中的人，而不是真实的人。
They're not the actual person that they are they're playing a character the actor or actress plays the
他们不是真正的人，他们正在扮演演员扮演的角色
character.
特点。
I have actors I need to put also actresses Here the actor or actress plays the character and the character
我有演员我还需要放女演员在这里演员或女演员扮演角色和角色
is the one in the story.
是故事中的那个。
The trailer is what you see before the movie comes out.
预告片是你在电影上映前看到的。
So when you talk about a movie we say blah blah blah is coming out soon it's coming out soon.
所以当你谈论一部电影时，我们会说 blah blah blah 即将上映，它很快就会上映。
I can't wait until whatever movie comes out.
我等不及要上映什么电影了。
I can't wait until it comes out because because I saw the trailer and the trailer is so good.
我等不及它出来了，因为我看到了预告片，预告片太棒了。
Can you say preview.
你能说预览。
Yes.
是的。
If you want to say preview.
如果你想说预览。
That's OK.
没关系。
So some people would say that the trailer is different than the preview.
所以有人会说预告片和预告片不一样。
People often just use trailer and preview to mean both.
人们通常只使用预告片和预览来表示两者。
There is often a difference in how long they are but it's not really that important.
它们的长度通常有所不同，但这并不那么重要。
People use these pretty much to mean the same thing.
人们几乎用这些来表示同样的事情。
I can't I can't wait to see.
我迫不及待地想看看。
I'm not going to say a name here because if you're watching this 30 years from when it's recorded then
我不会在这里说出一个名字，因为如果你正在观看这 30 年后的记录，那么
this whole series will look ridiculous.
这整个系列看起来很荒谬。
I can't wait to see blah blah blah movie name because the trailer looks great or awesome great or awesome
我迫不及待地想看到诸如此类的电影名称，因为预告片看起来很棒或很棒很棒或很棒
or whatever you want to say.
或任何你想说的。
OK.
好的。
Can't wait means you're very excited for that.
等不及意味着你对此感到非常兴奋。
Yeah OK.
是的，好的。
So that's how you would describe that.
这就是你描述的方式。
So what about series.
那么系列呢。
Can we use it for movies and TV.
我们可以将它用于电影和电视。
The answer is yes you can say my favorite TV series is you can say my favorite series of movies is but
答案是肯定的 你可以说我最喜欢的电视剧是 你可以说我最喜欢的电影系列是 但是
it has to be more than one movie.
它必须不止一部电影。
And usually it's many movies for example the Harry Potter movie series.
通常是很多电影，例如哈利波特系列电影。
People often call it a series of movies.
人们通常称其为系列电影。
I love the Harry Potter series.
我喜欢哈利波特系列。
In fact that can also be used for the Harry Potter books.
事实上，这也可以用于哈利波特的书籍。
OK now for TV we often call the show itself a series.
好吧，现在对于电视来说，我们经常将节目本身称为一个系列。
Sometimes people use show sometimes they use series.
有时人们使用节目，有时他们使用系列。
Many people use the word show when each one is completely unrelated to the others.
当每个人都与其他人完全无关时，许多人会使用“展示”这个词。
Every single one is completely different.
每一个都是完全不同的。
Maybe it's a game show or maybe it's a show where you just have a different sort of topic for each episode
也许这是一个游戏节目，也可能是一个节目，每集都有不同的主题
which we'll talk about next.
我们接下来会谈到。
But for a TV series it's usually a continuous story.
但对于电视剧来说，它通常是一个连续的故事。
One story that has multiple seasons and the season is one year for that show or that series.
一个故事有多个季节，并且该节目或该系列的季节是一年。
So if we're talking about a TV series where maybe every episode the next thing is happening based on
因此，如果我们谈论的是一部电视剧，其中可能每一集接下来的事情都基于
the previous one.
上一个。
And we have some some characters who are all the same.
我们有一些完全一样的角色。
And there's one story there is there's one kind of line or plot that's moving along.
那里有一个故事是否有一种线或情节正在移动。
And then in this season you'll have a very exciting ending.
然后在这个赛季你会有一个非常激动人心的结局。
And then you say oh I can't wait until next season.
然后你说哦，我等不及下个赛季了。
I can't I can't wait.
我等不及了。
I can't wait until Season 9 to come out to your waiting and you're waiting and you're waiting because
我等不及第 9 季出来了，你在等待，你在等待，你在等待，因为
you've seen seasons one through eight and the story's really interesting and you've fallen in love with
你看过第一季到第八季，故事真的很有趣，你已经爱上了
all the characters.
所有的字符。
That means you just really like the characters and each little story within each one of those is called
这意味着你真的很喜欢这些角色，每个角色中的每个小故事都被称为
an episode.
一集。
That's what an episode is usually.
这就是一集通常的样子。
Episodes are used for TV not used for movies but there are some examples where episodes are actually
剧集用于电视而不用于电影，但有一些示例实际上是剧集
used for movies too like Star Wars Episode 1 episode 2 episode 3 an episode as each piece of that.
也用于电影，例如《星球大战》第 1 集第 2 集第 3 集一集作为每一集。
So we could say an episode each little contained story is this big season is this big and the whole
所以我们可以说一集每个小故事都是这个大赛季是这个大而整个
series is this big.
系列就是这么大。
This is the whole thing.
这就是全部。
So now let's talk about how we can actually use actors and actresses their names and connect them to
所以现在让我们来谈谈我们如何实际使用演员的名字并将他们联系起来
the TV shows or movies they're in so we could say stars in or plays as I mentioned before we can use
他们所在的电视节目或电影，所以我们可以说我之前提到的明星或戏剧，我们可以使用
plays.
戏剧。
So let's say let's choose a person here.
所以假设让我们在这里选择一个人。
Let's say Hugh Jackman Hugh Jackman as an actor.
假设休·杰克曼作为演员休·杰克曼。
That's a real person.
那是一个真实的人。
Stars in a movie or the movie called Wolverine.
电影或电影《金刚狼》中的明星。
So I'm just going to fill this in here.
所以我要在这里填写。
Hugh Jackman stars in a movie called what's going on right here Wolverine.
休·杰克曼出演了一部名为金刚狼的电影。
That's the name of the movie.
这就是电影的名字。
I didn't really like the movie by the way.
顺便说一句，我不是很喜欢这部电影。
Anyway it was OK no it wasn't.
无论如何，没关系，不，不是。
It wasn't that good.
它不是那么好。
OK.
好的。
Hugh Jackman stars in a movie called Wolverine which is set in.
休杰克曼主演了一部名为金刚狼的电影。
And then you can say where it takes place or when it takes place.
然后你可以说出它发生在哪里或何时发生。
Or you could just say Hugh Jackman stars in and then you could cancel all of this and just say Wolverine
或者你可以直接说休·杰克曼出演，然后你可以取消所有这些，只说金刚狼
and then instead of saying which is set in saying where it takes place you could say which is about
然后你可以说它发生在哪里而不是说哪个是关于
a mutant who lives for a very long time and blah blah blah.
一个活了很长时间的变种人，等等等等。
You can talk about the story.
你可以谈谈故事。
Now let's use a classic example let's use Kate Winslet.
现在让我们使用一个经典示例让我们使用 Kate Winslet。
OK so Kate Winslet a very good very good actress.
好的，所以凯特温斯莱特是一个非常好的非常好的女演员。
OK let's use Kate Winslet plays.
好吧，让我们使用凯特温斯莱特的戏剧。
OK.
好的。
Now we could say something about the character.
现在我们可以谈谈这个角色了。
So this one the plays allows us to describe a little bit the character in the movie or TV series plays
所以这部剧可以让我们稍微描述一下电影或电视剧中的角色
a young rich girl.
一个年轻的富家女。
So abbreviate that as young rich girl.
所以简称为年轻的富家女。
Why are g if anyone ever asks you what is why are g me now you know plays a young rich girl named you
为什么 g 如果有人问你为什么 g 我现在你知道扮演一个名叫你的年轻有钱女孩
know the name classic movie Rose.
知道经典电影玫瑰这个名字。
OK Rose who.
好的玫瑰谁。
What does she do.
她是做什么的。
Falls in love with a young man named Jack in the classic film Titanic.
在经典电影《泰坦尼克号》中爱上了一个名叫杰克的年轻人。
So this is the structure that we can use and again you can say this whole thing or you can cancel it
所以这是我们可以使用的结构，你可以再说一遍，或者你可以取消它
which is also very common.
这也很常见。
This person stars in this which is about or this person plays a that other character details named character
这个人出演这个关于或者这个人扮演一个其他角色细节的角色
name who then something the character does in the movie.
说出角色在电影中所做的事情。
Then you could say in the film Titanic or in Titanic you can just say in Titanic.
然后你可以在电影泰坦尼克号中说，或者在泰坦尼克号中你可以在泰坦尼克号中说。
So this is very simply how you can describe characters and the actors or actresses who play those characters
所以这是非常简单的描述角色和扮演这些角色的演员的方法
in films and TV series.
在电影和电视剧中。
Very very common.
非常非常常见。
There's a word here that I didn't mentioned before because I forgot.
有一个词h之前我没有提到，因为我忘记了。
So let me just tell you what that one means that is sequel.
所以让我告诉你那是什么意思是续集。
OK sequel a sequel is one a movie usually that comes after another the original.
OK sequel 续集通常是一部接连不断的电影。
So you have the original and let's say we're talking about the movie bad boys.
所以你有原版，假设我们正在谈论电影坏男孩。
I've never actually seen it.
我从来没有真正见过它。
It's a pretty old movie.
这是一部很老的电影。
I've never seen it.
我从来没见过。
OK.
好的。
So the original is just called Bad Boys because they don't know if they're going to make another movie.
所以原版只是被称为坏男孩，因为他们不知道他们是否会制作另一部电影。
But then it's very successful.
但后来它非常成功。
It has huge box office success.
它取得了巨大的票房成功。
Actually I don't know if this movie had huge box office success just choosing this example.
其实我不知道这部电影是否仅仅选择了这个例子就取得了巨大的票房成功。
That means that it was very successful and made a lot of money.
这意味着它非常成功并且赚了很多钱。
OK.
好的。
Was a very big movie that made a lot of money.
是一部非常大的电影，赚了很多钱。
This is sometimes called a blockbuster.
这有时被称为重磅炸弹。
A very big movie maybe a superhero movie makes a lot of money.
一部非常大的电影也许一部超级英雄电影会赚很多钱。
Huge movie.
巨大的电影。
It's a blockbuster.
这是一部大片。
OK so this is the original and then oh it did very well.
好的，这是原来的，然后哦，它做得很好。
Very successful.
非常成功。
Everybody likes it.
每个人都喜欢它。
So we're going to come out with another one.
所以我们将推出另一个。
We're going to come out with a sequel a sequel.
我们将推出续集。
What will it be called.
会叫什么。
How about bad boys too.
坏男孩也一样。
Notice that it's often written like this instead of writing bad boys too.
请注意，它通常是这样写的，而不是写坏男孩。
Sometimes it's written like this.
有时会这样写。
And if you want to do your own research about this I don't want to teach you all these because it's
如果你想对此进行自己的研究，我不想教你所有这些，因为它是
not that useful.
没那么有用。
These are called Roman numerals and u m e r a l s good research Roman numerals and learn it.
这些被称为罗马数字，你可以很好地研究和学习罗马数字。
So when you maybe are in America and you see the Super Bowl is going on and it shows one of these big
因此，当您可能在美国时，您会看到超级碗正在进行中，它显示了其中一个
numbers it's a Roman numeral.
数字是罗马数字。
You'll know what it means.
你会知道这意味着什么。
Pretty simple actually pretty easy to learn.
很简单其实很容易学。
Takes ten minutes.
需要十分钟。
So the sequel of Bad Boys 2 was just as good as the original the sequel of Bad Boys 2 was not nearly
所以坏男孩2的续集和原版一样好坏男孩2的续集差一点
as good as the original was just as good as the original.
和原版一样好就和原版一样好。
Not nearly as good.
几乎没有那么好。
What the sequel.
什么续集。
The sequel.
续集。
The sequel if it comes before sometimes we have what we call a prequel and a prequel a prequel is made
续集，如果它出现在有时我们有我们所说的前传和前传，前传就会被制作出来
after but it's about what happens before it's made after.
之后，但它是关于在它之后发生之前发生的事情。
But it's about what happens earlier maybe to the characters when they were young star wars would be
但这是关于早期发生的事情，也许在他们年轻时的角色星球大战会是
a good example of that.
一个很好的例子。